endicott.edu 2013-05-14

# Endicott College - Privacy Statement

This Privacy Policy applies only to information you provide to us online while visiting or using our Web site. It does not apply to information we have obtained offline, or through other traditional means.   
_  
_**1\. Overview**

We have organized the elements of our Privacy Policy in sections. We have also included a variety of links in the body of our Privacy Policy, to connect related provisions and further assist in you in navigating and understanding the Policy. If after reading through the Privacy Policy you still have questions, please feel free to contact us by writing to the email and/or mailing address provided in Section 7 ("Contact Us"). 

**2\. The Types Of Information You Potentially May Provide**

Information you may provide in visiting our Site falls into two broad categories: personally identifiable information, and aggregate information. "Personally Identifiable Information" is information that can be used to identify or contact you, such as your name, email address, or mailing address. "Aggregate Information" is information that does not identify you, and may include, for example, statistical information concerning the web pages on our Site that users most frequent. Our Privacy Policy governs both categories of information, as detailed below.  
**  
2.1 Information That Identifies You: Personally Identifiable Information**

We allow you to decide whether you wish to provide us with Personally Identifiable Information. Accordingly, we have structured our Web Site so that you may visit us, and review a range of information about educational programs and services offered by Endicott, without revealing your identity or providing any Personally Identifying Information. 

One of our goals in creating this Web site, however, is to identify and establish contact with prospective students interested in studying at Endicott and to establish and maintain contact with enrolled students and alumni. Therefore, as you become more involved in our Site, we may ask that you register and provide us with contact and other information, as provided below. 

**2.1.1 Applicant Information**

Our primary form for gathering personal data is our on-line admissions application. In the Application Form people who wish to apply for admission to Endicott are asked to provide a range of permitted Personally Identifiable Information including but not limited to first and last name, birth date and social security number. The data obtained through the Application Form is only used internally at Endicott. The data is stored for review purposes only by admission officers working for Endicott. This data, while it is stored, may also be used for review and statistical analysis purposes and could be used for potential follow up mailings relating to a person's interest in Endicott College. This data is stored for a limited time before it is purged from the database. Should you want this information deleted, you should follow the directions set out in Section 2.2 ("How to Remove Your Information From Our Database").

If you have any questions or doubts you should direct them to the Director of Web Development at [webmaster@endicott.edu](mailto:webmaster@endicott.edu) with a message stating your concern or question.

**2.1.2 Email, Direct Communications and Other Forms**

We also gather personal information through the use of other Forms ranging from very simple email forms to more extensive requests for information. Use of any information entered on a Form is determined by the information owner of the particular Forms page. For example, the Alumni Office collects data primarily for the Alumni Office contact information updates for their own alumni mailings and related uses. Any questions about the use of this data by the Alumni Office should be directed to that office at [alumni@endicott.edu](mailto:alumni@endicott.edu)

In addition, you have the ability at our Site to pose certain questions to staff in order to learn more about educational programs, admission process and other services offered by Endicott. You may wish to provide us with comments and feedback concerning our Site generally. By communicating with us in these ways, you may provide us with your email address, and other Personally Identifiable Information. All data collected is secured at the highest level of security available to our webserver. We will handle Information that you provide in this manner in accordance with our Policy for Personally Identifiable Information, set in Section 2.3 (We Use Your Contact Information to Keep You Informed").

As indicated above, you may use our Site without registering or submitting any information to us. In that case, the only information we collect from your visit will be Aggregate Information, that does not identify you in any way. Our obligations concerning, and permitted uses of Aggregate Information are set out in Section 3 ("Information That Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information").  
**  
2.2 How To Obtain Access to Information You Have Provided, And How To Remove Your Information From Our Database**

Finally, if you request, we will remove your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our databases. Please understand, however, that it may be impossible to remove this information completely, due to backups and records of deletions. If you wish to remove your name and other Personally Identifiable Information from our database, please create an email with the term "Remove" in the subject line, and send the email to the address listed in Section 7 ("Contact Us"). As an alternative, you may write to us with your request, at the mailing address listed in Section 7 ("Contact Us"). You will be removed from our databases generally within three business days of our receipt of your request. 

Because Aggregate Information does not personally identify our users, we do not provide our users with access to Aggregate Information, and users may not update, revise, or delete any Aggregate Information.   
**  
2.3 We Use Your Contact Information To Keep You Informed**

We will use Personally Identifiable Information you give to us to provide you with information concerning educational programs and services, newsletters, updates, and related materials. We may also use this Information to respond to questions and comments from you, and to inform you of changes to our Privacy Policy. 

You are free at any time to opt-out of receiving email and other information we may send to you by following the directions set out in Section 2.2 ("How to Remove Your Information From Our Database"). 

We will not sell or disclose any Personally Identifiable Information you provide at our Site to any unrelated third party without your express permission, as set forth more fully in Section 2.4 ("No Unrelated Third Party is Given Access to Your Personally Identifiable Information"). 

**2.4 No Unrelated Third Party Is Given Access to Your Personally Identifiable Information**

We do not share with unrelated third parties any Personally Identifiable Information you provide to us. By "unrelated third parties" we mean anyone who is not involved in running the Endicott Site, or not involved in fulfilling requests you make at our Site.

We have relationships with certain providers who assist us in, or are responsible for, designing and maintaining the Site, responding to email and user inquiries, and disseminating newsletters and information related to the educational programs and services offered by Endicott. In order to carry out their responsibilities, these providers on occasion will require access to our users' Personally Identifiable Information. To ensure that our Privacy Policy continues to protect Personally Identifiable Information accessed by these providers, we require that all of our providers abide by our Privacy Policy, and prohibit our providers' use of any information, including Personally Identifiable Information, for any purpose other than providing us with goods or services related to Endicott.

**2.5 Any Information Linked With Your Personal Information Is Protected As "Personally Identifiable Information"**

To advance our educational and other goals, we may link (a) the Personally Identifiable Information you have provided; with (b) Aggregate Information concerning (for example) your interests and preferences, as collected through our cookies. Linking this information will allow us to create information packages and services that are better tailored to your interests and preferences. Among other effects, linking this information may allow us generally to improve and focus our Site and analyses.

If we combine or link any information with your Personally Identifiable Information, the resulting combination will be treated, and protected, as Personally Identifiable Information under this Privacy Policy. Accordingly, no unrelated third parties will have access to this Information, and any of our providers who are granted access to this information will be bound to protect it in accordance with this Policy, as set forth in Section 2.4 ("No Unrelated Third Party is Given Access to Your Personally Identifiable Information").

**3\. Information That Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information**

When you browse our site, the choices you make may provide information concerning your interests, and concerning the appeal and efficacy of associated Site features. For example, if you spend time browsing information on "academics," this suggests that this topic may interest you generally. If a number of visitors spend time browsing our features on " academics," this suggests that we have designed this portion of our Site effectively. 

Information concerning our visitors' activities at our Site - which pages they visit, and how long they view these pages, for example - is Aggregate Information. This information does not identify a particular user, but does provide potentially useful data concerning our users' preferences and the efficacy and interest of our Site's features. The manner in which we collect Aggregate Information is set out in Section 3.2 ("Cookies").

**3.1 We Use Aggregate Information Only In Ways That Do Not Identify You**

To measure our visitors' interest in and use of various areas of our Site, and for other purposes set out below, we collect Aggregate Information -- which is information that does not identify you. Aggregate Information obtained through cookies, for example, allows us to monitor how many users are visiting our Site, and what areas of the Site present the most interest to our users. We are able then to use this information to improve the functionality and interest of Site. We also use Aggregate Information to prepare statistical and other summary analyses of our users' behavior and characteristics. 

We may share Aggregate Information, and reports based on this Information, with third parties unrelated to the Site. Rest assured, however, that no information which we provide to third parties will allow anyone to identify you, or determine anything personal about you. For example, we might report to unrelated third parties (a) the number of users of our Site; (b) the materials our users review while at our Site; or (c) the fact that "45% of our users live on the East Coast" or that "25% of our users are interested in Graduate Programs." We may charge third parties for this Information, and we may or may not limit the third parties' use of this Information. We do not allow third parties to attempt to make Aggregate Information personally identifiable by, for example, seeking to combine it with other information.

**3.2 Cookies**

We may collect Aggregate Information about your use of our Site through cookies and similar Internet technologies. "Cookies" are small text files that a Web site can use to recognize repeat users, to facilitate the user's ongoing access to and use of the site, and to compile aggregate data to improve the site and focus advertising. Cookies work as follows: a Web site will send a cookie to your browser that uniquely associates your computer with information stored at the site. Your browser places the cookie in its cookies file. When you next access that site on your computer, the site recognizes the cookie, makes the stored information available, and adds new information based on the present visit. 

If we use cookies, they do not collect or retain your name or other Personally Identifying Information. In addition, no third parties are permitted to use cookies we may create at our Site for their own purposes.

We treat all information that may be collected through cookies and similar Internet technologies as Aggregate Information; our obligations concerning, and permitted uses of Aggregate Information are set out in Section 3 ("Information That Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information"). 

**3.2.1 Disabling Cookies**

You may choose not to allow us to collect information in this manner, through cookies. If you wish, you can set your browser software to reject cookies, and most browsers provide instructions for disabling the cookies feature in their "Help" section. Because cookies can be used to provide certain functionality, if you disable your browser's cookies feature, certain elements of our Site may be unavailable to you. 

**3.3 IP Addresses**

A so-called "Internet Protocol" (IP) address is associated with your computer's connection to the Internet. We use your computer's IP address to maintain contact with you as you navigate through our site. We also may use your computer's IP address to provide you with personalized content. Similar to cookies, your computer's IP address by itself does not identify you personally. We treat IP addresses, therefore, as Aggregate Information, as provided in Section 3 ("Information That Does Not Identify You: Aggregate Information "). If your IP address is combined with any Personally Identifiable Information, the combined information will be treated as Personally Identifiable Information, as set out in Section 2.5 ("Any Information Linked With Your Personally Identifiable Information is Protected as "Personally Identifiable Information"").

**4\. How We Safeguard Information We Collect**

We have put in place security systems designed to prevent unauthorized disclosure of information you provide to us. These systems are structured to deter and prevent hackers and others from accessing this information. Due to the nature of Internet communications and evolving technologies, however, we cannot provide, and disclaim, assurance that the information you provide us will remain free from loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties who, despite our efforts, obtain unauthorized access. 

**5\. Additional General Provisions**

**5.1 Privacy Protection for Children**

Our Site is not directed at children, and we will not accept or request personal information from individuals we know to be under 13. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, if we learn that a child under 13 has provided us with Personally Identifiable Information, we will delete this information from our databases, in accordance with our deletion policy, set out in Section 2.2 ("How to Remove Your Information From Our Database"). 

For more information regarding a child under the age of 13 providing personal information to a Web site, see the Federal Trade Commission's Web site explaining the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 at <http://www.ftc.gov/ogc/coppa1.htm>.

**5.2 Participation in Online Discussions**

If we add a "chat" or "forum" feature to the Site, you may decide to participate in an online discussion. Please keep in mind that any information you provide while participating in an online chat or forum will be available to all participants. These participants, and their transferees, may use Personally Identifiable Information and other information you disclose in this manner, to contact you and for other purposes. Accordingly, if we choose to provide such features at our Site, we ask that you participate prudently, as this Privacy Policy will not cover the information you disclose in online discussions at our Site. 

**5.3 Links To Other Web Sites**

To give you access to study abroad program information, information about hotel accommodations, directions to the College, and to provide you with other related information, we have included on the Web Site certain links to other sites. We provide these links as a convenience, and Endicott does not endorse the content or services offered by, or the privacy policies in place at, these other sites. 

Our privacy policy covers only information we collect at our Site, and other sites to which we link may have privacy policies that differ considerably from our Privacy Policy. We have structured our Site to make it reasonably clear when you leave our Web Site and enter another Web site. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each site you visit through our links, to ensure you are comfortable with these policies. We are not responsible for the conduct or policies of these third parties.  
**  
5.4 Court Orders, Subpoenas, And Other Required Disclosures**

There are two exceptions to our Privacy Policy. First, we may disclose Personally Identifiable Information as may be required in legal proceedings, or in response to a subpoena, court order, or administrative order compelling disclosure. Second, in cases involving a threat of imminent harm to you or others, we may release such Information to prevent or mitigate the threat. In any such case, we will seek to limit the scope of disclosure, and will disclose only such Information as is reasonably required to fulfill the purpose of the disclosure.   
**  
5.5 Changes in Our Privacy Policy**

From time to time we may revise our Privacy Policy. We will notify registered users of these changes, and will post the changes here. Any changes to our Privacy Policy will apply prospectively, and we will maintain Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with the version of the Policy in effect at the time you submitted the information, unless you consent to application of the revised Policy.   
**  
5.6 Complete Agreement**

In addition to this Privacy Policy, your use of our Site is also subject to our Terms and Conditions of Use (our "Terms and Conditions"). Together with our Terms and Conditions, this Privacy Policy constitutes the entire agreement between you and Endicott with respect to use of the Endicott Site. 

**6\. Your Consent**

By using our Web Site, you consent to our collection and use of information, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with some, or all of the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from becoming a registered user, or from visiting our Site. 

**7\. Contact Us**

You may contact us, for any reason, by email as follows:   

Gary F. Kelley  
Chief Information Systems Officer  
Endicott College  
376 Hale Street  
Beverly, MA 01915

©2004 Endicott College All rights reserved.
